Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
- Benjamin Franklin Miscellaneous Collection, 1710-1793; Mss.B.F85.[numeral]; 531 items
  - Letter to William Strahan, 1755 March 23; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Letter serves to cover a Bill of exchange for 20£.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, vol.V,535.
  - 1755 April ca., AD, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Memorandum relative to the reforms in connection with the delivery of mail.
    Printed: (under date of April [1743]) Labaree, Papers, II, 376-378.
  - Commission to [John] Read, as waggon master; Fort Cumberland, 1755 May 21; DS, 1p.; Braddock, Edward, 1695-1755
  - Pass for John Bickner and John Myfield permitting them to go to the new road in Cumberland county for clearing same, 1755 May 30; ADS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Mr. Samuel H. McVitty, March 1955.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, VI, 66-67.
  - Letter to Susanna Wright, [1755? June] Monday morning; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Julian P. Boyd, July 1947.
    From original in possession of Frank Jewett Mather.
    printed: Smyth,v.3,p.261.
  - Letter to Rich[ar]d Peters, [1755 Aug.]; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to the delivery of certain letters. "They hope the Colonel [Dunbar] does not mean to come to Philade. but only into this Province to be near the Magazine at Shippensburgh..."
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, VI, 128-129.
  - Certification that wages are due to John Read for his services as wagon master during the Braddock campaign, 1755 Oct. 1; ADS, 1p.; Scott, Thomas
    Scott was wagon master general.
  - Letter to Jona[tha]n Williams,Boston; Philad, 1755 October 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    "Free B Franklin". Sends printing paper to be sold.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, VI, 226.
  - Letter to James Read, 1755 Nov.2; ALS, 5p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Morris Duane; Dec.1962.
    Printed, with slight changes, and omission of P.S.:Smyth,vol. 3, 295-6.
    Labaree, Papers, VI, 234-236.
  - Letter to Rich[ar]d Peters, 1755 November 5; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges Peters' intentions to provide the bearers of the letter "with what Arms and immunition they have occasion for, provided the Assembly will engage to pay for them."
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, VI, pp. 236-237.
  - Recommendation of Benjamin Franklin for election to membership in the Royal Society of London, 1756 Jan. 29; Photograph of D.S: Macclesfield.. .P. Collinson and others. 1p.; Parker, George, 2nd earl of Macclesfield, 1697-1764
  - Letter to [Jane Mecom], 1756 February 12; Repro. of ALS. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Consolation on the death of their brother. Source of image (Batchelder Cat. #56, n.d.).
    1. Mecom. Jane, 1712-1794. I. B. Franklin chron.
  - Will, 1756 February --; D.S. 1p.; Sober, Sarah
    Seal Witnessed: Deborah Franklin, John Morgan Certification, Phila., October 3, 1757, S:William Plumsted.
    Mentions Benjamin Franklin and Richard Peters.
  - Letter to Miss Hubbard, [1756 February 22]; Copy of typed L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Taken from the Massachusetts Centinel, May 15, 1790. Presented by J.B.Nolan; May 1960.
    Printed: Smyth, III, 329-330.
    (see Mass.Magazine; Feb.1789,p.100.)
  - Position of troops in Northampton Co, [1756 February]; Photostat of A.D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In Connection with this document see article by William A. Hunter, "Two 'new' Franklin manuscripts,"
    Photostat presented by Mr.Hunter, 1953.
    From original in the Pa. State Archives, Papers of the Provincial Council, Harrisburg.
    Printed: Pennsylvania Archives, under date of 1758, Ser. I,v.3,325.
  - Letter to Elizabeth Hubbard (sic), dated Philadelphia, 1756 March 5; ALS, 1p. 0.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    shall send a commission to cousin Tuthill [Hubbart]; could be glad to have the state of the office accounts and the balance... Elizabeth Hubbart later became Elizabeth Partridge. Purchased at the Parke-Bernet sale, October 12-13, 1938, $55.
    Printed: Roelker's Franklin-Greene Correspondence,p.26
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, VI, 421-422.
  - Letter to B. F[ranklin], 1756 Sept. 8; Photostat of extract of L. 1p.; Clapham, William
    Presented by W.A. Hunter, June 1954.
    From original in Papers of the Provincial council, Division of Public Records, Harrisburg, Pa.
    Printed: Pennsylvania archives, II,766.
  - Minutes of Conference with Indians, held at Easton, Pa, 1756 November 15; Photostat of extract, in handwriting of Benjamin Franklin. 3p.; Pennsylvania. Provincial Council
    Presented by Dr. William A. Hunter, May 1954.
    Original in Pa. hist. and mus. com., Dept. of Public Records, Papers of the Provincial council. Text incorporated in Provincial Record, P, 89-90.
    Printed: Colonial Records, 7,330. Text is substantially the same as that in treaty printed by B. Franklin, Phila. 1757; Labaree, Papers, VII, 18-21.
  - Letter to Betsy Hubbard, 1757 January 13; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Advice for story-tellers; old age.
    Printed: Labaree, VII, 95
  - Letter to Earl of Loudoun; Woodbridge, 1757 May 21; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Delay in sailing of packet. Suggests that someone be appointed to enquire into the claims of the masters whose servants have been taken into service from Pa.
    From Loucoun papers, Huntington library. Press ented by E.M.Riley, August 1951.
    Printed: Labaree, Vol. VII, 214-5.
  - Receipt to Nathaniel Moore, 1757 May 23; Ms. D. (signature in handwriting of David Hall) 1p.; Franklin and Hall
    Subscription to the Gazette.
  - Letter to Jane Mecom, 1757 May 30 (?); Photostat of extract of L. Portion of p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From extract in New England Historic Genealogical Society.
    On same sheet with extract of letter of July 1, 1789.
    Printed: Smyth, v.3,404.
  - Invoice to the Library Company of Philadelphia, 1757 Sept. 22-1762 July 28; Copy of A.D.S. 1p. 9x6.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (From Charles Hamilton, Auction no. 77, May 2, 1974.)
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin ?], 1757 Oct. 16; L. 1p.; Hubbart, James
    Safe arrived in Halifax. News of French and English action in and near the city. Death of Capt. Lewis.
  - Letter to B[enjamin] Franklin, 1757 Nov. 12; Typescript of L. 1p.Extract.; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Concerning the Aurora Borealis.
    Presented by Francis D. West, 1953.
    (from original in Royal Society, London.)
  - Letter to [John] Pringle, 1757 December 21; Photostat, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in Royal Society of London; read and presented to the APS by Lord Adrian, April 20, 1956.
    Printed: Smyth, 3, 425; Franklin, Experiments...on electricity, 1769.
  - Letter to David Hall, 1757 December 9; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printing matters; European affairs. Purchased from W. B. Ingham, March 1941.
    Printed:Labaree, Papers, vol. VII ,237-8.
  - Letter to Mr.[John] Waring, 1758 January 3; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Proposed school for negro children in Philadelphia sponsored by the Associates of Dr.Bray. Transcribes extract of letter from Mr.Sturgeon, August 22,1757.
    Printed: Labaree, Paper vol. VII, p.356.
  - Letter to the Earl of Loudon, 1758 January 20; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
  - Letter to Deborah Read Franklin, 1758 January 24; Photostat, 1p.; Loudon, Earl of
  - Letter to J[ohn] Waring, 1758 February 17; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Advice on establishing a school for negro children. Mr. [Henry] Wheatly's legacy for James and Mary Hunter (?).
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, vol. VII, 377-9.
  - Commission to Woodward Abraham to the post of deputy post-master at Marblehead, Mass, 1758 April 10; Printed D. filled in and S: B.Franklin, William Hunter [post-masters-general]. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Seal. (Actually signed by James Parker for the post-masters general)
  - Letter to [Joseph] Galloway, 1758 June 10; ALS, Photostat. 2p. F.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Hears nothing of Mr. Hamilton's application for a charter for Phliadelphia from the Crown.
    The original of this photostat is in the Mason Collection at Yale University Library; photostat was purchased from the Library, October 1939, $ .60.
  - Letter to [David] Hall, Philadelphia, 1758 June 10; L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Trouble with Moore and Smith affair. His confidence in Hall. Business. Strahan will forward certain articles. Concerning a printer who may remove to America. Refers to "Billy".
  - to Mary [Stevenson], Tunbridge Wells, 1758 August 20; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Stifler, J.M. "My Dear Girl," p.18) (Printed also in Sparks, p.80)
  - 1758, ALS, 14p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Freeman Guide 969.
  - to [Mary] Stevenson, 1760 February 14; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Stifler, p.19) (Sparks, p.62)
  - Letter to Miss Stevenson, 1760 May 1; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 4,10.
  - Letter to William Cullen, 1760 Sept. 17; L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces the bearer, Mr. [William] Shippen who goes to Edinburgh for study of physick and surgery.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1760 Nov. 22; ALS, 1p.; Wright, John
  - Letter to Mr. [John] Winthrop, 1761 April 8; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Contains also drafts of letters from Winthrop to Franklin, Pringle, and Gov. Belcher.
    John Pringle's piece on fiery meteors Sands papers of Mr. Kennicott relating to the Hebrew Bible; inquires whether the college has any associated material.
  - Letter to John Balfour, 1761 April 2; ADrS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Eefers to payment of a bill received from David Hall. Written on back of letter from Balfour to Franklin, March 26, 1761.
    Purchased from W. B. Ingham, March 1941
  - Letter to Josiah Quincy, 1761 April 8; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Purchased at the sale of the Larkin collection, Kende galleries, Gimbel brothers, N.Y., May 1, 1942. No.A10.
    Printed: Smyth, v.4, pp.98-100; with variations in Quincy, J. Memoir of the life of Josiah Quincy June 1825, p.473-4
  - Letter to E. Pennington (sic), 1761 May 9; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 4,p.106.
  - to [Mary Stevenson], 1761 July 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, Jared, ed. A Collection of the familiar letters...of Benjamin Franklin, p.67)
  - Letters to Debby [Franklin], 1761 August 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Plans to set out in few days for Harwich; possibility of going to Holland.
  - Letter to [William] Cullen, 1761 October 21; L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth 4,116.
  - Letter to Mary [Stevenson], 1761 October 29; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed almost entirely: Smyth,4,117.
  - Letter to Lord Bessborough, Friday evening [ca. 1761]; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    According to recent commission, Mr. Hunter's decease has not caused a vacancy in the American postmastership - Franklin fills entire office.
  - to [Mary Stevenson], 1762 May 10; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to [Mary Stevenson], 1762 May 24; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.70; Stifler, p.55)
  - Letter to J[ohn] Winthrop, 1762 December 23; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Scientific and friendly news. Mentions his son.
    On same sheet are letters from Winthrop to B.Franklin; Jan 20,1763, and Winthrop to Short; June 6, 1764.
  - Order to Messrs. Hughes and Co., for a set of musical glasses, with directions for making, [ca. 1762?]; Photostat of A.D. 1p. Photostat of A.D. 2p. il.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    ---- Directions for making a musical machine. Presented by Whitfield J. Bell, Jr., 1956.
    From originals in the Assay Office, Birmingham, England. "Not to be reproduced without permission."
  - Letter to William Strahan, 1763 March 28; Enlargement print of ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania.
    Printed in part: Smyth, v.4,196.
  - to Mary [Stevenson], New York, 1763 June 27; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.83; Stifler, p.67)
  - Letter to Mr. [John] Waring, 1763 June 27; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    School for Negro children in Philadelphia; similiar institutions in New York, Williamsburgh, New York, and proposed one in Newport, R.I.
  - Letter to [Catherine Greene], 1763 July (sic) 23; Photostat of newsclipping.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From the Boston Post, ca. Jan.10, 1850.
    The text of this letter is the same as that from Franklin to caty of Jan.23, 1763 (of. B:F85.86 and Smyth, v.4,188)
    Contains also portions of letters from Franklin to caty or William Greene Feb.15. 1764 and Feb. 28, 1778.
    Letter printed also in Littell's living age,p.80,no.308,Apr.1850.
  - Letter to [William Greene], 1763 July 19; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 4,205: Roelker,36.
  - Letter to Jared Ingersoll, New Haven, 1763 July 25; ALS, 1p., add., end. 9x7-1/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Informs Ingersoll that "I shall ...call on my way home... about the Beginning of September." Mentions his daughter Sarah.
  - Letter to [Catherine Greene], 1763 Sept. 5; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    With this came a water color of the Franklin residence at Ecton, and a copy of T.B. Welch's engraving of the "thumb portrait" of Franklin owned by the APS.
    Printed: Smyth, v.4, 207; Roelker's Franklin-Greene Correspondence,p.38
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams [sr.], 1763 November 28; Photostat, 1p.F.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    domestic affairs.
    Printed: Smyth, V.4,209.
  - Letter to Mr. [John] Waring, 1763 December 17; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Reports on school for negro children in Philadelphia. Desires to be remembered to the Associates [of Dr. Bray].
  - Letter to Messrs Baynton, Wharton and Morgan, Philadelphia; Montreal, 1764 March 13; Photostat of L.S.: Samuel Eldridge and Will[ia]m Long. 3p., end. by B. Franklin.; Eldridge, Samuel
    Concerning business affairs in Canada.
    (from original document in Penna. Hist.and Museum comm. Public records division, Baynton,Wharton and Morgan papers.)
  - Letter to Mary Stevenson, 1764 March 14; ALS, 2p., end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth,
  - Letter to Cadwalader Evans, 1764 May 18; Facsimile of ALS, 1p. 6x3-3/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Thanks for plan of a furnace which should be published. Introduces Benjamin Rush.
    From Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc. catalogue Sale no. 3813B November 25, 1975, item 359.
  - to Mary Stevenson, Philadelphia, 1764 May 4; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.92)
  - Certification of sale of stock by the Phiadelphia Linen Manufactory to Charles Thomson, 1764 Aug. 13; D.S. 1p. 12x8.; Moore, Samuel Preston
    This company was formed by B.F. et al.
  - Letter to [Peter Collinson], 1764 Sept. 24; Typed L. 1p. Extract.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Francis D. West, 1953, from original in Royal Society, London.)
    Printed: Smyth, IV, 260-261.
  - Letter to Sally [Franklin]; Reedy Island, 1764 November 8; LS Cy 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth 4,286.
  - to [Mary Stevenson], [1764 December]; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.95; Stifler, 73)
  - [Plan for an American colonial paper currency.], [ca. 1764.]; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Photostat of document sold at the Gribbel sale on October 31, 1940; of. Parke-Bernet catalogue no. 223, item 252.
    Cf. W.R. Riddell, Benjamin Franklin and colonial money in Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, v. 54,1930,pp. 52-64.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1765 Jan. 8; ALS, 1p; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
    Franklin, Jan. 11, 1765 Answd. (BF's hand)
    Cold weather. Work on the house [in Franklin court]. News of family and friends.
  - to [Mary Stevenson], 1765 January 9; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.96; Stifler, p.74)
  - Philadelphia contributionship for the insurance of houses from loss by fire, 1765 Mar. 25; D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1786
    Received contents, March 29, 1765, by Franklin and Hall.
  - Letter to Dr.[Cadwalader] Evans, 1765 July 13; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    "The proceedings of those mad people on the frontier."
  - Letter to [John] Morgan, 1765 July 8; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Establishment of medical school in Philadelphia.
    Paid Morton's admission fee to the [Royal] Society.
  - Letter to Keziah Folger Coffin, 1765 August 29; Typed L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    With copy of note by Thomas F. Wood describing the document and giving its history.
    Sends gift.
    Micr. of copy, inserted in letter from W.C.Folger to J.Sparks;July 30,1838 (see Sparks papers...; reel 2, no.114.)
  - Letter to David Hall, 1765 Sept. 14; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to David Hall, 1765 November 9; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Purchased from W. B. Ingham, March 1941.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], 1766 Jan. 12,13; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
    Franklin's lands in Chester Co. and Nova Scotia. Appreciation for things received from Franklin. News of family and friends.
  - Letter to [Joseph] Galloway, 1766 January 16; Photocopy of ALS, (in BF's hand?); Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Discusses political relationship between Britain and the colonies; Stamp Act. Mentions Mr. Pitt, Messrs. Wharton, Mr. Hughes.
  - Letter to Joseph Fox, 1766 March 1; Enlargement of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Repeal of the Stamp Act.
    From original in possession of Mr. Logan Fox, 1956.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, New York, 1766 Mar. 4; A.L. in 3rd. P. 2p., end. 7-1/2x6.; Free, John, 1711-1791
    Forwards books for Dunscomb. but he may keep them if Dunscomb is dead. [Edwin Wolf 2nd identifies 4 of the 5 items as in B. Franklin's Library.]
    Presented by Morris Duane; Dec.1964.
  - Letter to M[atthew] Boulton, 1766 March 19; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Experiments in connection with steam engine.
    From original in Assay office, Birmingham, England.
  - Letter to the Committee of Correspondence, 1766 June 10; Photostat. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [Francois Ulrich Théodore] Aepinus, 1766 June 6; Printed L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From article in: Akademiya Nauk SSSR, Amerikanskiy Ezhegodnik, article by Bolkhovitinov.Original of letter in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    Thanks for his book on electricity. Praises it.
  - Letter to [François Ulric Theodore] Aepinus, 1766 June 6; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Thanks for his work in electricity and magnetism.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1767 February 18.; Photocopy, 1p.; Hughes, John. -1772
    Needs help due to results of "the Stamp Act Affair," and relies entirely upon Franklin.
  - Letter to Benjamin Gale, 1767 February 22; Photostat of printed L.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relates to a mistake in the Gentleman's magazine about Gale's success in inoculation. (APS has Gale's letter of November 15, 1766, to which this is a reply.
    Photostat of Connecticut Courant, June 26, 1769, presented by James Brewster, State Librarian, Connecticut State Library.
  - Letter to A[nn Vaux] Penn, Dublin, 1767 February 28; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerns Thomas Penn's proposed purchase of house and 500 acres of the land which belonged to his father. Refers to Pennington (sic), Mrs. Stevenson and her daughter.
  - Letter do "Dear sister" [Jane Mecom], 1767 March 2; ALS, 2p. slightly mutilated.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    His reaction to abuses he meets with "I number them among my Honours." Sends box of millinery bought for her by Mrs. Stevenson
  - to [Mary Stevenson], 1767 March 26; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.99; Stifler, p.75)
  - to Mary [Stevenson], 1767 May 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.100; Stifler, p.76)
  - to Mary [Stevenson], [1767?] May 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Same idea as previous letter, but worded differently)
  - Letter to Samuel Franklin, 1767 July 17; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Contains also copies of letters from Franklin to Sam. Franklin of June 8, 1770, July 12, 1771, July 7, 1773.
    From copy in New England Historic Genealogical Society.
    Printed: Smyth, v.5,35.
  - Letter to [Peter Collinson ?], 1767 October 14; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Arrangements for a visit to Mill Hill to see him and Dr. Solander.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] LeRoy, 1768 March 14; ALS, 2p. 12-1/4x8.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Thanks for his civilities. Concerning APS astronomical observations to be made in Philadelphia and difficulties involved. Refers to Julien LeRoy and his time piece.
  - Letter to [Deborah Franklin]; Pensilvania Coffee house, 1768 August 9; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Is extremely well. He must have patience about returning.
  - to Mary [Stevenson], 1768 October 20; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.116)
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], 1768 Nov. 6; Photostat of A.L. 3p.; Thomson, Charles, 1729-1824
    Positive and negative.
    Concerning the American Society, and the election of Franklin as president.
    From original in L.C.
  - Letter to Smith, Wright and Gray; [London], 1769 February 13; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Asks that a letter of credit be procured for Benjamin Rush; instructions regarding his [Franklin's] finances.
  - Letter to Messrs. [Samual ?] Wharton and [William] Trent, dated, 1769 July 3; ALS, 1p. 0. End: "Dr. Franklins card, July 3, 1769."; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    on advice of Mr. Mildred and his solicitor, Mr. Lane, concluded to withdraw the petition presented to the king in council on behalf of Messrs. Warder, Mitchel, etc.
    Purchased from F.G. Sweet, Sept.15, 1939, $67.50.
  - Letter to Humphrey Marshall, 1769 July 9; Photo. of ALS, 1p.(photo. contains also engraving); Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Mrs. William K. du Pont through P.S. du pont, November 1949.
    Printed: Darlington, Memorials of John Bartram and Humphry Marshall,1849,p.515.
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams [sr.], Boston, 1769 October 4; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    His add to Mrs. Williams' kin, the widow Johnson and her family. Public affairs.
  - Letter to Adolf Berzel[ius]; Saturday evening, [ca.1769 November].; Photocopy of AL in 3rd p. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin presents respects; will see Mr. Berzel. and friend tomorrow.
    Original in Kungliga Universities biblictetek, Uppsala.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers of BF. Yale Univ. Press, Vol.16, p. 252.
  - Letter to [Jane Mecom], 1770 December 30; LS Cy, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    "True copy from the original by Rebecca Burroughs, November 21, 1833"
    Printed almost in entirety: Smyth, 5,288.
  - Letter to [Humphry Marshall], 1770 March 18; T.C. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Ed. Bury Jan.1947.
    Printed: Darlington, Memorials of John Bartram and Humphry Marshall,p.516.